Abdullahi Hassan

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Experienced Business development executive with a degree in Business Economics and intends to work for a growing organization to accelerate self and company prospects. Committed to implementing change and completing production tasks before fast approaching deadlines. Skilled at working well under pressure and adapting quickly to change.

612-986-6446



Abdullahi.ibrahassan@gmail.com



Minneapolis, MN



EDUCATION

B.A of Business Economics

St. Cloud State University, USA Major: Business Economics Minor: Chain Supply Management CGPA: 3.82/4.00, Dean's Honors List Rank: Top 10 student ranked in Business Cohort

EXPERTISE

Written & Oral Skills Strong Attention to Detail Adept Multitasking Skills Strong Passion for Helping Others Works Well Under Pressure Reliable & Hard Working Ability to Follow Rules & Regulations **Internet Marketing Skills** Strong Leadership Skills Management Experience Team Oriented Data Entry Skills Data Analysis Skills

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Python Java Tableau

Statistical Analysis AWS (S3, Glacier, CF, EC2)

FB ads

Google AdWords

QuickBooks

Oracle

Salesforce

SharePoint

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Merrill Corp

Account Biller / St. Paul, USA- Minnesota |

Feb. 2018 - May 2019

Provided advance billing by integrating new processes in the organization while ensuring the availability and accuracy of the data. Assist various marketing teams to define and implement pricing programs as well as promotional opportunities. Support push to global initiative by ensuring all data is ready from legacy systems to the new unified Salesforce platform.

- Revised, inspected, and corrected mistakes in financial entries.
- Assist in compiling client list of existing grids.
- Participates in a team-based atmosphere and effectively works within a complex business structure
- Compare and analyze data lines with corresponding rates to grid pricing, and updates.
- Demonstrated creative thinking in all project deliverables to ensure projects are completed in a timely manner and efficiently.
- Salesforce Case Management.
- Monitor and follow up on client profiles and grids outstanding for approval, time allotments.
- Fluency in global client billing software systems; Including multi-currency billing
- Establishes relationships between internal customers (collections, sales, billing, credit, finance, accounting, customer service and production) and external customers (Merrill clients and vendors).
- Supported human resources staff with new hire orientations and monthly departmental meetings.

KAL Freight INC

Oct. 2016 - Jan 2018

Account Assistant/Manager / Fontana, California |

Responsible for all administrative duties including but not limited to general ledgers, DOT compliance, IFTA reporting, and driver payroll. Promoted to manager in July 2017.

- Inquiry, track, and resolve accounting problems
- Supported complex, deadline driven operations and independently resolved issues in a timely manner.

Trained personnel on how to maintain essential reporting along with proper DOT guidelines to ensure

- personnel safety. Processed daily driver logs for over 1,000 drivers. Followed up on any unacceptable driver logs as
- well as driver violations.
- Built and maintained database for all tractors (550 tractors) and renew lease annually.
- Completed weekly safety checks on 75 different vehicles with a value of over \$3.5 million in order to make sure all components were fully up to date.
- I improved staff productivity and efficiency by 20% maintaining vehicle Readiness for over 100+

Project Intern

Jun. 2014 - Sep 2014

Allina Health | Minneapolis, MN |

Responsible for managing project and collaborating cross functional with a diverse team to support assigned research studies of data management and analysis, communication, and admin assistance for research project.

- Effectively communicated with study team and assisted as a source throughout the conduct of the
- Generate reports to research manager, study sponsor, principal investigator, and key stakeholders as required
- Demonstrated a strong ability to perform tasks with minimal assistance and adapt quickly to change.
- Showcased dependability and flexibility by working 7 days on and 7 days off to serve as a resource for team.

LEADERSHIP EXPERIENCE

- Minnesota 2018 Transformational Leadership for Individual Contributors
- Founder of Non-Profit Organization Supplying Hope & Improving Poverty (S.H.I.P)
- Best Prep Non-Profit Organization Volunteer and Engagement Committee
- St. Cloud State University Corporate Council